<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stupid Things</title>
    <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On top of the Wold</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round18/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t think that there are a huge number of hills in Lincolnshire. According to the Marvelous Map of Great British Place Names, there is Nob hill, not too far from Poke Holes and Fanny Hands Lane. Unfortunately (for my childish brain), none of these are the highest point in Lincolnshire. Rather, it goes by the grand title of Normanby Le Wold Top (oooh, fancy!).
Some time ago during this hill running challenge, I had run up all of the hills that could realistically be reached from Cambridge (except Northamptonshire - the less said about that the better), without spending more time in the car than on the trails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Wood you do in Wales?</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round17/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a long way to Wales from Cambridge. It&amp;rsquo;s not so far that you have spend several days travelling to get there, the UK is, after all, quite small. It is far enough to be annoying to get to though. Getting anywhere from Cambridge used to be a lot worse than it is now (for non-native UK readers: the second most common conversation for Brits after the weather is about roads and traffic; we have a lot of that too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting saucy in Worcesterhire</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round16/</guid>
      <description>[Mike: I was too lazy to write this blog post - so I asked the lovely Julie if she wanted to do it, and she actually said yes!]
If I was going to do any of these runs with Mike, it was going to be Worcestershire, the place of my birth, the homeland. The highest point in Worcestershire is Worcestershire Beacon in the Malvern Hills, which form a long ridgeway along the Worcestershire and Herefordshire border.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a bunch of Kents</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round15/</guid>
      <description>As I write this, the world has gone through is in the throws of a global viral pandemic. How humanity comes out the otherside is a matter of pure speculation. The only thing that I know, is that if this doesn&amp;rsquo;t change how our society works, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what will.
This blog isn&amp;rsquo;t about SARS-CoV-2 (the virus responsible for the current state of affairs for future readers). It&amp;rsquo;s about running, hills and adventures on whatever scale you can manage them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A muddy eruption</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round14/</guid>
      <description>What do you do when you&amp;rsquo;re bored in January and live in Cambridge? Answer: drive for 2 hours to fulfill an idiotic challenge to run up an arbitrary number of hills based on a somewhat tenuous definition of a &amp;lsquo;highest point&amp;rsquo;. It just dawned on me that I can&amp;rsquo;t really justify this challenge, other than &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve started so I&amp;rsquo;ll finish&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s genuinely nice that people regularly ask me how the challenge is progressing, but I also get a little bit of a sense of disappointment when I tell them I&amp;rsquo;ve only run up 16/103 hills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun London</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round13/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time. That’s a terrible beginning for any story. But that’s the beginning of this story. A story of sights, sounds, and gingers. Let’s begin.
A wise man said that only a ginger may call another ginger “ginger”. He also said “cheese”, a lot, and had a penchant for lunging. This wise man’s name is Tim. Tim is an entertainer from a strange country called Oz. We went to see Tim in his “show” before we decided to run around our nation’s capital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warwickshire - A comedy of errors</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round12-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round12-md/</guid>
      <description>This will be a short post, as I’ve heard that brevity is the soul of wit (Hamlet).
It’s a long time between Christmas and Easter this year. Too long. It got to the point where both Julie and I were getting run down, so we planned an impromptu break to the Cotswolds and Stratford upon Avon - Shakespeare country! We found a cute little cottage called the Old Dairy, complete with it’s own massive cheese press in the bedroom - thankfully it hadn’t been used for some while so the aroma of maturing cheddar did not linger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutland - Small but perfectly formed</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round11-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round11-md/</guid>
      <description>Where the heck is Rutland? I hear you ask. Well, according to some, it is the smallest county in England, it holds the largest manmade lake (so basically half of it is a lake) and it is home to the Nurdling World Championships (Nurdling = throwing pennies in a hole), the winners are crowned the ‘best tosser’, no joke.
Based on these facts alone, this was shaping up to be a very exciting run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suffolk-ing boring</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round10-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round10-md/</guid>
      <description>After our high point of charging up Brown Willy (tee hee) on New Years day, we thought we&amp;rsquo;d keep the momentum going with another county hill. One that I ashamedly had not completed yet, despite planning the route when I first began this challenge: Suffolk.
So two weeks into the New Year we made the short drive from Cambridge to the little village of Hawkedon. We knew from the outset that this probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be the most exciting run, but we literally had nothing better to do on this crisp Sunday morning in January.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dirty brown willy</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round9-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round9-md/</guid>
      <description>[Insert standard excuses about writing a blog post months after the run]
Julie and I have a very similar sense of humor, so I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat ashamed that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed the county hill that would obviously be the most fun. Brown. Willy. tee hee hee. This hill, by far, was the most hotly anticipated for us. I think Julie spotted the name sometime in the summer. A very quick Google of Brown Willy (with the parental filters on), turned up a dream come true - the Brown Willy News Year day run!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BoGoF</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round8-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round8-md/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;rsquo;m getting too predictable. As I mentioned in my last blog post I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a rather annoying habit of writing these posts several months after the event. This has the rather irritating effect that I can only remember half of the details. Nevertheless, here goes&amp;hellip;
Buy One Get One Free The clock is ticking. It&amp;rsquo;s December 13th and I&amp;rsquo;ve only run 3 county hills all year. I said to myself at the beginning of the year that I would do at least 5, preferably more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wales 0 - 1 Mike</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round7/</guid>
      <description>It will come as no great surprise to my readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve run up another hill, and that I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post several months after the event. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is just my enthusiasm for this challenge waning (I assumed it would ebb and flow like the tides anyway), or that I&amp;rsquo;m just settling into a more realistic routine. There are 103 county tops on my list, and including the run I&amp;rsquo;m about to describe, I&amp;rsquo;ve only managed to run 8 of them so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never trust a golfer</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round6/</guid>
      <description>NB: I&amp;rsquo;m actually writing this 3 months after we ran this hill, mostly because life got a bit busy, we had a holiday in the Alpes, blah blah blah, the usual excuses. Anyway, here it is.
What better activity to do on the hottest May Bank Holiday on record, than go for a run? I think that this might count as a genuinely stupid thing to do, especially when you know it&amp;rsquo;s coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icy Death Wind</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round5/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a fun couple of months since my last hill challenge run back at Christmas. In that time I&amp;rsquo;ve trained for the Cambridge half marathon, it&amp;rsquo;s snowed, Julie and I moved in together (in the snow), and then we both ran the Cambridge half the day after (thankfully not in the snow; but it has snowed again since). This blog is called &amp;lsquo;Stupid Things&amp;rsquo;; I think running a half marathon the day after moving house, with just the two of us doing all of the lifting, counts as something stupid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two for the price of one</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round4/</guid>
      <description>2017 is over, and there&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big dent in January. I started my running challenge to try to motivate me back into running generally, hill running specifically, and because I like to tell people I think suffering is good for the soul. What better time of year to suffer, than Christmas? (I get on with my family pretty well, so they aren&amp;rsquo;t really a source of suffering tbh). Of course I&amp;rsquo;m talking about going for a windy, sleety run on Christmas day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Oxford</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round3/</guid>
      <description>Well it&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since my last official county hill run, 3 months by my reckoning. In all honesty that was maybe leaving it a bit too long, but I have to also be honest with myself; this is a long-term challenge. In those 3 months I have been keeping myself pretty busy, and my time was largely dominated by training and preparation for a week in the Alps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 1</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item1/</guid>
      <description>App 1 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 2</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item2/</guid>
      <description>App 2 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 3</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item3/</guid>
      <description>App 3 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 4</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/itemized/item4/</guid>
      <description>App 4 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>County number 2</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round2/</guid>
      <description>I have a confession to make. In my last post I told you that I had run up Great Chishill, that towering edifice of Cambridgeshire. I lied.
The hill in nearby Essex is called Chishill Common, and stands at a lofty 147m. Great Chishill is it&amp;rsquo;s little sister at 146m. They are both within a few miles of each other, so when I planned the route for my first foray into this project, I went looking for the highest point in that area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a computational biologist, runner and climber. This blog is mostly about a little running adventure I&amp;rsquo;m embarking on, but will likely be interspersed with other thoughts regarding climbing trips, and generally doing things that might be considered quite, quite stupid.
This is from an &amp;ldquo;incident&amp;rdquo; when some friends and I got stuck inside a storm in the volcanic crater of Mt Aragats in Armenia. It was a pretty stupid situation to find ourselves in&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round 1</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round1/</guid>
      <description>Great Chishill. It sounds like it should be some towering natural edifice, rather than a scrappy corner of a field next to a small copse of trees. It was a good start though, and perhaps a good way to revise my expectations a little. The lack of hills in and around Cambridge, and my distinct lack of fitness, made this a somewhat tougher challenge than I had expected.
I planned the route out yesterday after picking up a few OS maps from a local outdoor shop (there&amp;rsquo;s only one in Cambridge that actually sells maps, so no points for guessing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Why?! I think this might be the third blog I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to write. My previous attempts in the past suffered due to lack of a proper theme, motivation; well the usual issues that accompany a chronic lack of creativity.
I think (hope?) this one might be a bit different.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering a little running project for a few months, and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got off my bum and started to plan it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-install-hugo&#34;&gt;Step 1. Install Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;hugo releases&lt;/a&gt; and download the
appropriate version for your os and architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More complete instructions are available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/overview/installing/&#34;&gt;installing hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;move-static-content-to-static&#34;&gt;Move static content to &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; will be copied as-is to the &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; output. Hugo keeps all static content under &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;. You should therefore move it all there.
With Jekyll, something that looked like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/
    ▾ images/
        logo.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BoGoF</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round8-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round8-md/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;rsquo;m getting too predictable. As I mentioned in my last blog post I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a rather annoying habit of writing these posts several months after the event. This has the rather irritating effect that I can only remember half of the details. Nevertheless, here goes&amp;hellip;
Buy One Get One Free The clock is ticking. It&amp;rsquo;s December 13th and I&amp;rsquo;ve only run 3 county hills all year. I said to myself at the beginning of the year that I would do at least 5, preferably more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>