<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hills on Stupid Things</title>
    <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/categories/hills/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hills on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/categories/hills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On top of the Wold</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/post/round18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/post/round18/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t think that there are a huge number of hills in Lincolnshire. According to the Marvelous Map of Great British Place Names, there is Nob hill, not too far from Poke Holes and Fanny Hands Lane. Unfortunately (for my childish brain), none of these are the highest point in Lincolnshire. Rather, it goes by the grand title of Normanby Le Wold Top (oooh, fancy!).
Some time ago during this hill running challenge, I had run up all of the hills that could realistically be reached from Cambridge (except Northamptonshire - the less said about that the better), without spending more time in the car than on the trails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting saucy in Worcesterhire</title>
      <link>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/blog/round16/</guid>
      <description>[Mike: I was too lazy to write this blog post - so I asked the lovely Julie if she wanted to do it, and she actually said yes!]
If I was going to do any of these runs with Mike, it was going to be Worcestershire, the place of my birth, the homeland. The highest point in Worcestershire is Worcestershire Beacon in the Malvern Hills, which form a long ridgeway along the Worcestershire and Herefordshire border.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>